Toni Morrison Papers, 1957-: Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
- Series 7: Photographs, 1940-2012; more than 9 boxes (1 partial)
  - Oversize and Scrapbooks, 1985-2012; 1 item
    - University of Wisconsin, Madison, 1990 February; 1 item
    - Yale Commencement, 1985; 1 item
      3 black and white photographs; letter from Sharyn B. Wilson, dated June 28, 1985. Pictured: Ellen Ash Peters, Toni Morrison, Arnaldo Momigliano, A. Bartlett Giamatti, Marian Wright Edelman, Wolfgang K.H. Panofsky, Jerzy Turowicz, Howard H. Baker, Jr., Austin Ranney, Shridath S. Ramphal, Frederica von Stade, Ernest Kasemann.
    - Dinner, 1 item
    - Matted Snapshots, 1 item
    - Portraits, 1 item
      Black and white photographs. With note from Joshua S. Odell, Knopf.
    - James Baldwin in Istanbul, 1966 Summer; 1 item
      1 black and white photograph. Sedat Pakay, copyright 2009.
    - Gala to Salute Congress and the Arts, American Arts Alliance, 1989 May 2; 1 item
    - Toni Morrison Portrait, Rolex Mentor and Protege Arts Initiative, 2005; 1 item
    - Toni Morrison in Car, Union Square, New York, 2003 January 27; Lemaître, Pascal; 1 item
    - University of Pennsylvania Scrapbook, 1988 May 16; 1 item
    - The Dead of September 11, 1 item
      Published in Vanity Fair.
    - Sistren: Black Women Writers at the Inauguration of Sister President Johnnetta B. Cole, 1988; 1 item
      1 color photograph. Pictured: Louise Meriwether, Pinkie Gordon Lane, Johnnetta B. Cole, Paula Giddings, Pearl Cleage, Gwendolyn Brooks, Toni Cade Bambara, Sonia Sanchez, Nikki Giovanni, Mari Evans.
    - Opera Carolina Margaret Garner Scrapbook, circa 2006; 1 item
    - "Home!" Scrapbook, circa 2012; 1 item
    - SUNY Albany Album and Scrapbook, 1987; 1 item
- Series 8: Published Material (see C1491.1), 1 item
- Series 9: Press Clippings (see C1491.2), 1 item
- Series 10: Awards and Memorabilia (see C1491.2), 1 item
- Series 11: Toni Cade Bambara Papers, 1960-2005; more than 8 boxes (Box TCB 1-7)
  Drafts, proofs, and publication material relating to two works by Bambara edited and published posthumously by Morrison: Deep Sightings and Rescue Missions: Fiction, Essays, and Conversations (1998) and These Bones Are Not My Child (working title: Ground Cover) (1999); as well as Morrison's Random House author file on Bambara, circa 1970-1980 and correspondence between Bambara and Melvin Wilk, dating from 1960-1995.
  - These Bones are Not My Child, MSS, undated; 6 folders (Box TCB 1, Folder 1-6)
    Contains prologue, notes and newspaper clippings throughout
  - These Bones are Not My Child, Correspondence, 1998-1999; 1 folder (Box TCB 1, Folder 7)
  - These Bones are Not My Child, MSS as "Ground Cover," 1-150, 1997; 6 folders (Box TCB 2, Folder 1-6, Box TCB 3, Folder 1-2)
  - These Bones are Not My Child, Draft, undated; 3 folders (Box TCB 3, Folder 3-5, Box TCB 4, Folder 1-4)
  - These Bones are Not My Child, Proofs, 1999 April 10; 2 folders (Box TCB 4, Folder 5-6, Box TCB 5, Folder 1-2)
  - These Bones are Not My Child, Advance Copy, 1999 June 23; 1 folder (Box TCB 5, Folder 3)
    Signed by Toni Morrison
  - These Bones are Not My Child, Production Design, 1999-2000; 1 folder (Box TCB 5, Folder 4)
  - Short Stories, Copies of Original MS Drafts, 1996; 1 folder (Box TCB 5, Folder 5)
  - Short Stories, MS, undated; 1 folder (Box TCB 6, Folder 1)
  - Short Stories, Earlier MS, undated; 2 folders (Box TCB 6, Folder 2-3)
  - Deep Sightings and Rescue Missions, Copy of Copyedited Version, 1996 June 12; 1 folder (Box TCB 6, Folder 4)
  - Author File, 1971-1978; 2 folders (Box TCB 6, Folder 5-6)
    Contains royalty, copyright and payment documents and some correspondence and drafts of writing
  - Toni Cade Bambara and Melvin Wilk Correspondence, 1960-1995; 1 folder (Box TCB 6, Folder 7)
    Transcribed letters TCB wrote to Melvin Wilk from June 1960 to August 1995 and correspondence between TM and Wilk from 2002
  - Toni Cade Bambara Memorial Transcript, undated; 1 folder (Box TCB 7, Folder 1)
  - Press and Correspondence, 1981-2005; 1 folder (Box TCB 7, Folder 2)
    Largely regarding These Bones are Not My Child, but not exclusively.
  - Press, 1997-2002; 1 folder (Box TCB 7, Folder 3)
    French and English language press
- Series 12: James Baldwin Correspondence and Estate File, 1957-2014; 1 box (Box JB 1)
  Photocopied correspondence from Baldwin, dating from 1957-1986; materials relating to the Baldwin Estate, adminstered by Gloria Karefa Smart.
- Phase 2: Working Files, 1977-2011; 1 item
  - Books, 1977-2011; 1 item
    - The Bluest Eye, 1980-2007; 1 item
      - Adaptation by Lydia Diamond, 2005-2006; 1 item
      - Brenda McGee Scores, 2003-2004; 1 item
      - Censorship, 1994; 1 item
      - Lorraine Hansberry Theatre, 1987-1989; 1 item
      - Picador/Vintage, 1990-2007; 1 item
      - Plume, 2005; 1 item
      - Screenplay Requests, 1980-1992; 1 item
    - Sula, 1984-1995; 1 item
      - Catalan Translation, 1995; 1 item
      - Film, 1984-1994; 1 item
    - Tar Baby, 1982-1995; 1 item
      - Contract Info re: Adaptation, 1982; 1 item
      - Film Inquiries, 1986-1995; 1 item
      - French Translation, 1986; 1 item
    - Song of Solomon, 1977-1996; 1 item
      - Book of the Month Club, 1977; 1 item
      - Oprah Book Club Reading Group Guide, circa 1996; 1 item
      - Press Schedule, 1977; 1 item
      - Price Intro Copy, Correspondence re: Adaptation, 1984-1995; 1 item
    - Beloved, 1986-2006; 1 item
      - Arabic Translation, 1990; 1 item
      - Correspondence and Press, 1986-2006; 1 item
      - Demme, 1998; 1 item
      - Harpo, 1992-1997; 1 item
      - Gottlieb, Robert, undated; 1 item
      - NYPL Corporate Lions, 1989; 1 item
      - Press, 1987-1988; 1 item
      - Signet, 1990; 1 item
      - Teacher's Guide, 1991; 1 item
    - Jazz, 1991-1997; 1 item
      - Correspondence, 1992; 1 item
      - Book Party, 1992; 1 item
      - Excerpt, undated; 1 item
      - Denver Reading, 1992; 1 item
      - 92nd St. Y Reading, 1992; 1 item
      - London/Paris, 1992; 1 item
      - Chatto & Windus Tour, 1992; 1 item
      - Michigan/Toronto, 1993; 1 item
      - Germany/France Tour, 1993; 1 item
      - Sweden/Norway, 1993; 1 item
      - Knopf USA, 1991-1992; 1 item
      - Knopf Canada, 1992; 1 item
      - Picador/Chatto & Windus, 1992-1993; 1 item
      - Franklin Library, 1992; 1 item
      - Audio, 1991; 1 item
      - Paper--Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, 1991-1992; 1 item
      - Dutton/Signet, 1997; 1 item
      - Italian Translation, 1993; 1 item
    - Paradise, 1997-1999; 1 item
      - Knopf Domestic Tour, 1997-1998; 1 item
      - Knopf Domestic Tour Publicity, 1998-1999; 1 item
      - Reader's Guide, 1997; 1 item
      - Knopf Canada, 1998; 1 item
      - Plume, 1998; 1 item
      - Book Party, 1998; 1 item
      - Publication Denial, 1998 February 20; 1 item
      - California Tour, 1998; 1 item
      - UK Tour, 1998; 1 item
      - Germany/Italy Tour, 1999; 1 item
    - Love, 2003-2005; 1 item
      - Correspondence, 2003; 1 item
      - Knopf Working Files, 2003; 1 item
      - Reading Princeton University, 2003; 1 item
      - 92nd St. Y Reading, 2003; 1 item
      - Domestic Tour Schedules, 2003; 1 item
      - UK Working Files, 2003-2004; 1 item
      - Vintage Working Files, 2004; 1 item
      - Foreign Working Files, 2004-2005; 1 item
      - Italy Mantova Book Festival, 2004; 1 item
      - France/Spain Tour, 2004; 1 item
    - A Mercy, 2006-2009; 1 item
      - Correspondence, 2006-2008; 1 item
      - Publicity, 2008; 1 item
      - Editorial, 2008; 1 item
      - Chatto Editorial, 2008-2009; 1 item
      - 92nd St. Y Reading-12/8/08, 2008; 1 item
      - Random House Audio, 2008; 1 item
      - Pam Houston Interview/ O Magazine-4/7/09, 2009; 1 item
      - B&N Vintage Paperback, 2009; 1 item
      - Knopf/Random House Canada, 2008; 1 item
      - European Tour/Curtis Brown, 2008-2009; 1 item
      - France-5/9-17/09, 2009; 1 item
      - Holland 5/17-21/09, 2009; 1 item
      - Italy 5/21-24/09, 2008-2009; 1 item
      - European Press, 2009; 1 item
      - Interviews, 2009; 1 item
      - Foreign Press Requests, 2009; 1 item
      - National School Boards Association-4/5/09, 2008-2009; 1 item
      - Translation Queries, 2008-2009; 1 item
      - Press, 2008; 1 item
      - Orange Prize Longlist-6/3/09, 2009; 1 item
    - Home, 1 item
      - French Translator's Questions, undated; 1 item
      - Vintage Reader's Guide, undated; 1 item
    - The Big Box, 1987-2001; 1 item
      - d'Amboise, Jacques, 1987; 1 item
      - Correspondence, 1998-1999; 1 item
      - ICM, 1999-2001; 1 item
      - Press, 1999; 1 item
    - Book of Mean People, 1999-2003; 1 item
      - Book Expo America, 2002; 1 item
      - Correspondence, 2000-2002; 1 item
      - ICM, 1999-2002; 1 item
      - Press, 2002-2003; 1 item
    - Who's Got Game, 2002-2005; 1 item
      - Correspondence, 2002-2005; 1 item
      - NBA Read to Achieve, 2004; 1 item
    - Remember, 2003-2005; 1 item
      - Correspondence, 2003-2005; 1 item
    - Peeny Butter Fudge, 2008-2011; 1 item
      - Correspondence, 2008-2011; 1 item
      - Tour, 1 item
      - Simon & Schuster, 2009; 1 item
    - The Black Book, 2008-2009; 1 item
      - Foreword, 2008-2009; 1 item
      - NPR Interview, 2009; 1 item
  - Alpha Working Files (see C1491.2), 1 item
- Phase 2: Audiovisual Material (see C1491.1), 1 item
- Phase 2: Born-digital Material (see TMalldisks.xml), 1982-2000; 1 item
  Related material: WordPerfect for IBM Personal Computers Version 5.0 copyright 1988 manual; five WordPerfect 5.0 Princeton University software disks; Symantec Q&A Version 4.0 (3 1/2" format) manual.